globalforestwatch.org 2013-10-16

# WRI Community: Privacy Policy - World Resources Institute

WRI respects the privacy rights of our online visitors and recognizes the importance of protecting the information we collect about you.

World Resources Institute (WRI) respects the privacy rights of our online visitors and recognizes the importance of protecting the information we collect about you. This policy statement tells you how we collect information from you and how we use it. 

WRI only collects personal information from our online visitors on a voluntary basis and only when:

  * contributing information for site registration and future updates; 

  * submitting feedback and comments; 

  * completing surveys; 

  * placing orders for materials; 

  * donating through our web sites.

Personal information collected may include your name, your organization, email address, phone number, address, and specific information about how you found our site and how you might use our materials. We do not generally require this information to obtain access to any of our sites. In most cases, we will also ask if you would like to receive email from us and give you the option of designating “yes” or “no”.

World Resources may also collect demographic information from visitors, such as age, gender, geographic location, interests, or what platforms you own. This information helps us to improve our online offerings and allows us to tailor information to your preferences.

Visitors contributing online or purchasing items through our online bookstore will need to provide a valid credit card number and expiration date in addition to name, mailing address, phone number and email address. Please note that you must be over the age of 18 to give or place orders online. All financial information is encrypted and transmitted by SSL protocol via World Resources Institute’s secure server.

## Data collection and sharing

WRI does not sell our customer lists. We may disclose user information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) WRI’s rights or property, other WRI users or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. At any time you can correct, update or remove your personal data by contacting Laura Lee Dooley (please include a copy of the most recent correspondence from WRI).

## Security

Security is of the up most importance and concern to us. Credit card information is transmitted via SSL (secure socket layer) encryption. SSL encryption is a method by which information is encrypted while being transmitted over the Internet. It is the industry standard in e-commerce at this time. Credit card information is kept on file in an encrypted format for a maximum period of 30 days, after which it is automatically deleted and no longer retrievable by WRI’s customer service.

To review personal information collected or request corrections you may login to community.wri.org or contact:

Devan Tucker  
CRM Manager  
+1(202)729-7658

## Your Acceptance of These Terms

By using this site, you signify your assent to the WRI’s Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.
